<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Earth's Magnetosphere</title><link>https://vibhav19.github.io/magnetosphere/</link><description>Recent content on Earth's Magnetosphere</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-IN</language><copyright>All rights reserved - 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vibhav19.github.io/magnetosphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Details</title><link>https://vibhav19.github.io/magnetosphere/post/2022/11/29/test/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhav19.github.io/magnetosphere/post/2022/11/29/test/</guid><description>Earth’s internal magnetism creates a region around the planet known as the magnetosphere. While several planets in our solar system have magnetospheres, Earth has the strongest one of all the rocky planets: Our magnetosphere is a vast, comet-shaped bubble, and it has played a crucial role in our planet&amp;rsquo;s habitability.
Life on Earth initially developed, and continues to be sustained, under the protection of this magnetic environment. The magnetosphere shields our home planet from harmful solar and cosmic particle radiation, as well as erosion of the atmosphere by the solar wind – the constant flow of charged particles streaming off the Sun.</description></item><item><title>More About Magnetosphere</title><link>https://vibhav19.github.io/magnetosphere/post/2022/11/29/test/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vibhav19.github.io/magnetosphere/post/2022/11/29/test/</guid><description>Our magnetosphere is part of a dynamic, interconnected system that responds to solar, planetary, and interstellar conditions – and it all starts deep inside Earth. As electrically charged, molten iron churns far below Earth’s surface, within the planet’s outer core, it generates a magnetic field large enough to extend far out into space. On the Sun-facing side of Earth – where the magnetic field is compressed by the constant bombardment of the solar wind – the magnetosphere extends some 6 to 10 times the radius of Earth.</description></item></channel></rss>